KUSHAGRA CHOPRA

Buffalo • 7166031324 • kushagrachopra069@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/kushagrachopra069 • https://kushagra123.github.io/KushagraResume.github.io

SUMMARY

Kushagra completed his undergraduate degree in Computer & Communication Engineering from Manipal Institute of Technology. He started his career as a Software Intern at Cerner Healthcare, where he later worked as Software Engineer for a year. Kushagra is currently pursuing a Master's degree in Computer Science from University at Buffalo, NY and is expected to graduate in February 2020.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cerner Healthcare Solution Ltd. – Bangalore, India

July,2017 - May,2018

Software Engineer, C# developer – Cerner Instant Access

- Developed and Deployed Cerner IA Configuration GUI, a WPF application in .NET framework, that serves as one of the 3 main components of Cerner Instant Access. It could store multiple user profiles for one or many applications, providing required security layer to upheld user data privacy.
- Developed and Deployed Dragon Medical One Launcher as a WPF application that launched DMO on startup based on user credentials used to login into the device.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, upgrade interfaces and improve performance.

Cerner Healthcare Solution Ltd. – Bangalore, India

Jan,2017 - June,2017

Software Intern, C# developer

• Developed a WPF application known as Instant Access Installer, under the mentorship of IAccess team. It could install all components of "Cerner Instant Access" and also setup required third party components that support the IAccess workflow. Both GUI based and silent install capabilities were provided to user.

EDUCATION

University at Buffalo, NY, USA

2018 - Present

Masters in Computer Science & Engineering

• Relevant Coursework: Algorithm Analysis & Design, Advanced Information Retrieval, Computer Security, Data Intensive Computing, Distributed Systems, Object Oriented Design.

Manipal Institute of Technology, Karnataka, India

2013 - 2017

Bachelor of Technology – Computer & Communication Engineering

- Relevant Coursework: Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Advanced Programming Technologies,
 Parallel Programming, Data Mining & Predictive Analysis, Information Retrieval, Operating System.
- A member of the technical team at Indian Society of Technical Education, Manipal.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Web mining and Social Media mining for text extraction & summarization[Python, Flask Framework,
 BeautifulSoup, NLTK, Spacy, Gensim, Glove Word Embedding, HTML5, CSS3, Twitter API, JavaScript, Apache
 Solr]: Developed an end-to-end system that crawls through multiple news websites and Twitter to collect
 textual data for election-based riots, which is then processed to extract key information like event location,
 date, entities involved, and create a summary of each news article to be displayed on the UI along with analysis
 like time-line and location distributions.
- Complete Search and Analytics Solution based on dissecting twitter data[Python, Flask Framework, HTML5, CSS3, Twitter API, JavaScript, Amazon AWS, Apache Solr]: Developed a web application deployed on Amazon EC2 Server that performed Sentiment Analysis, Distribution Graphs based on location and language for each search query. Tweet Data was retrieved using Twitter API and Indexed using Apache Solr.
- **Designing and Deploying a Service-Based Distributed Systems** [Python, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, MongoDb]: Involved developing a client-server application involving use of Google Maps API and OpenWeather API to show weather along a user-defined route. Stored distinct results using MongoDb for future use.
- Emulating Pub/Sub Distributed System using Docker Containers [Python, Flask Framework, Docker ToolBox, HTML5, CSS3, AJAX, JavaScript]: Involved developing a Distributed Publish-Subscribe interface as a client-server application that were executed and interacted amongst multiple docker containers.

• Data Collection & Analysis using R and Twitter Data [R, RStudio, Jupyter Notebook, Twitter API]: Collected twitter data using relevant terms and processed it to plot a map of USA with a gradient representing the quantity of tweets with respect to flu from each state, this was later compared to the CDC data for the last year to see how reliable social media is in terms of finding a trend for flu in the USA.

SKILLS & TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language: Python, C#, Java, C++, SQL, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python, R, Solidity. **Software**: Microsoft Visual Studio, Android Studio, Eclipse, PyCharm, MongoDb, MySQL, Oracle SQL Server, Citrix Receiver, Apache Solr, Apache Hadoop, Docker Toolbox, VirtualBox, Amazon EC2, Git, JIRA, RapidMiner, Cisco Packet Tracer, Remix IDE, TortoiseSVN, Jupyter Notebook, SQLite, WireShark, Microsoft Office, IBM InfoSphere, OpenCV2.